i did a lot of work with prudential of
america back in the 70s and early 80s
and
their sales were not by hundreds of
millions of dollars one one xvp said he
thinks it went over a billion dollars i
was showing them how to alter their
condition behavior
and their sales just went crazy
but when i talked about the oscar i was
thinking about that company they had
what was called the trophy
the president's trophy
there was one trophy given out for
vice presidents
senior vice presidents there was one
trophy given out for managers there was
one trophy given out for sales managers
there was one trophy given out for
agents so on every level in the company
there was only one trophy and that was
to the numero uno the number one
then they had
an award
for the
top 10 percent
and
i'd spoken at a convention i was living
in los angeles here
but i'm from toronto and the office out
of houston
their regional office was holding their
conferences in toronto at the hyatt i
said i'm from toronto i'd love to do it
so i was going to work there for a
couple of mornings
for each region one region to move out
another one would come in
well this one guy when they announced
that i was going to be working for two
and a half hours this day
he said god that's going to be
dull
you know i hope this guy
you know
knows how to find another job because
he's not going to last here
well after the meeting
this same guy
company said can i talk to you for a few
minutes
i said okay but i got to get a hell out
of here because there's a lot of these
people want to talk to me so i said i'll
meet you in the coffee shop so we met in
the coffee shop just inside the coffee
shop
he said
before i ask you what i would like you
to share with me he says i want to tell
you something about me
he said
i've been with this company for 22 years
24 years i've been in management for 22
of the 24 years and he said i'm a damn
good man
and you could look at this guy you would
hire him on site he looked like a real
solid guy
and he said i do a good job
but he said
i stand i think it was 285
in the company
and we said that's not bad out of
510 districts or something like that
said my district stands 285.
he said i'd like to think
that i could get
one award
before i retire
now to do that you had to be in the top
10 percent you'd only give it out to i
think 55 districts
and that was all over the world
this is the number one insurance company
the largest insurance company in the
world
and
i said then i could show you how to do
that in about 15 minutes
he'd been working at it for 22 years
every day he had been working on it
but he was working the wrong way
if he had to work for 44 years he'd have
never made it happen he was doing the
wrong things
he was violating the law he was trying
to get
i said that doesn't that dog won't hunt
you just can't do it
i said
you told me you were 285.
i said what you have to do you have to
see yourself in the top fifty you have
to see yourself where you want to be
you've got to live like that person
like
you know
william james from harvard way back in
1900 he says the actor's technique
act like the person you want to become
i was talking to an actress a couple of
days ago fairly well known one
and i said
let's think of a stage play
you've gone to the theater
now
let's think there's three or four of us
involved in this one scene
and
three of the people are really into this
they know their lines
they've got into character
i've known my lines intellectually i've
memorized them and i can say them
but i'm not
really in character i just have the
words
and i'm just saying
the words
the audience would say where the hell
did they find that guy
i would stand out
like
a beacon on a dark night
where all the rest of the actors are in
character they're really into it they're
living it
i would just be saying it
i said this guy that's what you're doing
you're saying where you want to be
i said you've got to be there
you've got to be there you've got to
treat the people like they have
taken the district to that level i said
you've got to walk that way you've got
to talk that way you've got to actually
live it
it if you don't it is never going to
happen because you've been trying for 22
years
and we had him write out
a statement
i am so happy now
that i am and being where he wants to be
now he was in wichita kansas
he said where are you working i said i'm
next week i'm in
i'm working with mid-america and going
to be in litchfield illinois he said
could i come and travel with you
well i said i'm not really too fond of
you doing that but okay
you know like i didn't you know when
you're finished you want to be finished
you want to go and
relax
but anyway he came he sat through the
seminar we traveled we were driving we'd
do an all-day seminar and then maybe
drive 300 miles to get to the next one
to work all the next day
i keep telling the people in our company
you got no idea what this was like when
we started and
anyway
um
he traveled with me for about four days
and then he went home
and they moved him to pittsburgh kansas
now
pittsburgh kansas
60 to 70 of the population had an income
below the national poverty level
it's a little wee place out in the
middle of nowhere
the first year
he went to
something like 52 or something like that
the next year
he was number one in the world
number one in the world
beat all the districts new york chicago
los angeles
big cities i said it makes no difference
doesn't matter where you are
i said what the hell they're skiing in
over in the desert in dubai
snow skiing
[Music]
it's in here
paul hutsey
is his name
you can get away with blaming conditions
or circumstance yourself
but
not with spirit